Rishab Baisakh

16-4140, chemin de la Cote-Sainte-Catherine, Montreal, QC, H3T 1E3

(514) 576-6004

rishab.baisakh@gmail.com

https://github.com/RishabBaisakh

- English, Hindi, Oriya

Professional Profile:

A Programmer keen on writing the least code possible with the laziest possible approach, currently inclined towards Web Development with more than 1 year of professional experience. I have completed an Attestation of College Studies Degree in Programming Web and Technologies. Major skill set includes JavaScript, and one of its libraries, ReactJS. I believe in absolute fun and personal development while working.

Technical Skills:

Languages : JavaScript, JAVA, C, C++, PHP, SQL

IDEs : Microsoft Visual Studio, Android Studio, Eclipse

Design Patterns: Singleton, Observer/Listener, MVC, MVVVM, Builder,

Lazy Loading

Frameworks: ReactJS, AngularJS 2+, JQuery, Bootstrap, Unity, Zend

Database: MySQL, Firebase

Version Control : Git

Education:

Programming and Web Technologies | Institute Superior de Informatique

(2019 - 2021)

Bachelor's in Computer Science & Technology | Visveswaraya Technological University

(2014 - 2018)

Projects:

Toon Racing | Unity

A 3D car racing game for Windows built with Unity. 2 major aspects of the game includes the Player car and the Artificial Intelligence controlled car. The game consists of two maps.

The design mainly consists of Waypoint system with Vector Calculation, Conditional Monitoring System, and Artificial Intelligence Perseption.

I was involved in end-to-end project, from graphics to writing C# scripts, all alone.

Slack (Clone) | ReactJS

A chat application built with ReactJS and Firebase. One can create chat rooms to connect with a number of users. It has been deployed using Firebase.

The design consists of React Context API, Material UI, Google User Authentication, and Firestore.

I was involved in Full-Stack functionality of the app, all alone.

Github: https://github.com/RishabBaisakh/slack-clone

Spotify (Clone) | ReactJS

A music streaming application build with ReactJS and Spotify Web API. The project mainly focuses on frontend and display data from a user's actual Spotify account including account information, playlists, etc.

The design mainly consists of React Context API, Material UI.

I was involved in all the functionalities of the application that has been developed so far, alone.

Github: https://github.com/RishabBaisakh/spotify-clone

WhatsApp (Clone) | ReactJS, NodeJS

A chat application built with MERN stack, where anyone can connect with their fam via personal messages. One can also make groups and chat together.

The design consists of React Context API, Material UI, NodeJS as backend and MongoDB as database.

I was involved in complete full stack functionalities of the application, alone.

Github: https://github.com/RishabBaisakh/whatsapp-clone

Work Experience:

Organization: Flexiele Consultancy Pvt. Ltd.

(August, 2018 - August, 2019)

Data Analyst, Front-End Developer

The FlexiEle, is a product based start up, with an open work environment. The product was a Human Resource Management System.

First six months, I was a hired as a Data Analyst, and with an ability to write PHP scripts. Most of my work required me to produce tuned SQL queries. Within the first two month, I was incharge of an entire domain, that is generating Excel reports using PHP-Excel library.

For the latter six months, I was given an upportunity to be a part of the Development team for the new application. I worked as a front-end AngularJS 2+ Developer.

Other Work Experience:

Mid-Cite Rentals and Sales Ltd.

(July, 2020)

Wordpress Website Support

I was given an opportunity to support and extend the functionalities of an already setup Wordpress website. I also managed the to an ad campaign for the business using Google Adwords.

Freelance

(September, 2019 - December, 2019)

Web Developer

I have developed a portfolio website for an artist, using Javascript, and PHP. I also deployed it.

Summary:

I have a very methodical approach towards doing anything in my life. This also helps my team, as the documentation plays a key role in the development of any application. I have been mastering **JavaScript** for more than two years now. I love programming and mathematics. I would like to a part of a good development team and learn more.